In the last lecture we added the code to get some data,
Son derste baz verileri almak iin kodu dzenleriz.
of course that is a huge first step but it would be even more useful if we could write that data to
Tabii ki bu byk bir ilk adm ama ekrana yanstabiliyor ve yerini alsayd
the screen, if it could render it to the screen and replace this array of dummy posts here with a dynamically
bu veriyi ekrana yazabilseydik daha yararl olurdu, burada Dammy yaynlarnn bir n, burada yaynlara
generated array based on the posts we fetched. For this, we need to manage some state of course and we
dayanan dinamik olarak oluturulmu dizi ile sergilendi. Bunun nedeni, baz halleri ynetmek zorunda olduumuz ve
should have some posts in that state,
bu eyalette baz yaynlarmz olmas gerektiidir.
initially this can be an empty array.
Balangta bu bo bir dizi olabilir.
Now I want to update this state once we fetch data from the server and therefore the place to call this
imdi sunucudan veri getirdiimde bu durumu gncellemek istiyorum ve bu nedenle bu
set state is inside the then method.
ayar durumunu armann yeri u yntemin iindedir.
If we would call it outside of this, so after this axios get method, we wouldn't have the post yet because
X-ers Meffert' almazsa, daha nce bahsettiim ey yznden depostuzun
of the thing I mentioned earlier.
olmayacan syleyebilirdik.
The code javascript doesn't wait for this to finish so if you're immediately calling this set state after the
Kod javascripti, bunun bitmesini beklemiyor, bylece get ynteminden hemen sonra bu ayar
get method, the data won't have been fetched yet.
durumunu arrsanz, veriler henz getirilmemi olur.
So inside the then blog is the right place and there we can set posts to response data,
Dolaysyla, o zaman blokun iinde doru yer var ve yant verisine mesajlar ayarlayabiliyoruz.
you just saw in the console that the data property is available on that response object and that the
Konsolda, veri mlknn bu yant nesnesinde bulunabileceini ve veri
data property holds an array of posts. So I'll comment out the response logging and instead set my state
mlkiyetinin bir dizi ileti tuttuunu grdm, bylece yant gnln yorumlayacam ve durumumu
to the posts.
postalara ayarlayacam.
Now let's output posts dynamically in the render method, for that
imdi gnderileri dinamik olarak render ynteminde iletelim.
I'll create a new constant here, posts, and that should be an array of jsx elements. So I will use this.
Mesajlarnza yeni bir sabit oluturacam ve GSX elerinin bir dizi olmas gerekir, bu nedenle devlet eyaletlerini bu
state.posts, the state,
durumu belirtmek iin kullanacam.
we just updated it with the server data and there as you learned it, call the map method to map it
Bunu sadece sunucu verisi ile gncelledik ve orada rendiiniz gibi bunu eitli x elerinin
into an array of jsx elements and the map method of course returns a new array which I store in
bir dizisine elemek iin harita yntemi deniyor ve elbette harita yntemi tablonun
the posts constant.
saklad yeni bir dizi dndryor.
Now in the map method here,
imdi harita ynteminde.
I get my individual posts as an input in that function we're passing to the map method and there I want
aktardm ilevi girdi olarak alyorum ve x eleman olarak bir j dndrmek istiyorum.
to return a jsx element.
Bireysel yazlarm, harita yntemine
I want to return my single post here
Tekli postuma burada dnmek istiyorum.
like this, down there
Aada olduu gibi.
I then of course want to output this array of posts which is stored in that posts constant.
Tabii ki bu posts dizisinde depolanan bu dizi diziyi kt yapmak istiyorum.
Now this post should of course at least output the title,
imdi tabii bu yaz en azndan balk kt.
if we inspect the post component, we see an output title here.
Grev bileenini incelersek, burada ini ktsn grrz.
So therefore here,
Bu nedenle senin.
I probably want to get some props, maybe a props with the name title.
Muhtemelen sahne balklar olan bir sahne alm yapmak istiyorum.
So it should pass this title property to the single post,
Pasters, mlkiyetin tek bir deftere yazlmasn gerektirir.
so in the blog container, I need to set a title property here and pass post.title, the title
Blok konteynerinde burada bir balk zellii ayarlamalyz ve bu yazy, bu yaz elemanndaki
property on this post element is available because of the data we fetched from the server just to reassure
balk zellii yalnzca sizi rahatlatmak iin sunucudan aldmz verilere gre retti.
you already got spoiler that it worked.
Bozuldunuz, ie yarad.
But the data that we get back from the service is this array and each element here has a title property.
Ancak bugn Desirae hizmetinden geri dndk ve burada her enin bir mlkiyet hakk var.
So as you can clearly see, it already works here.
Aka grebileceiniz gibi, burada zaten alyor.
Styling is a bit off,
ekillendirme biraz kapal.
we also output all the posts which might be too much and we haven't set the key prop,
Ayrca, ok fazla olabilecek ve dzgn tutmak iin ayarlamadmz tm mesajlar yaynlyoruz.
so let's fix these three things.
Bu  eyi dzeltelim.
Let's set the key prop
Anahtar ayarlayalm.
and as you can verify by checking out the data we get back from the server,
Ve verileri kontrol ederek dorulayabilecei iin sunucudan geri dnemiyoruz.
you'll see that there also is an id property on each post.
Her yayda id zellii olduunu greceksiniz.
That of course makes up for a perfect key because it's unique.
Elbette mkemmel bir anahtar oluturur, nk bu esizdir.
Now regarding the styling and the amount of posts, for the styling, let's go to the post component and
imdi stil ve stil iin yaynlarn miktar ile ilgili olarak, posta bileene gidelim
change the width to maybe 250px,
ve 2 belki 250 piksel ile deielim.
now they have a little bit more room for the title.
Artk ampiyonlua biraz daha yer var.
Still there are too many posts and that is something I'll take care about in the next lecture
Yine de ok fazla mesaj var ve bu bir sonraki dersde ilgileneceim bir ey.
when I show you how to transform the data you get back.
Size geri dn verilerini nasl dntreceim gsterirken.